<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulation on Pedro N. de Lima</title>
    <link>/tags/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simulation on Pedro N. de Lima</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Factory Physics&#39; Flow Benchmarking in R</title>
      <link>/post/factory-physics-flow-benchmarking-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/factory-physics-flow-benchmarking-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Flow Benchmarking is an absolute benchmarking technique that allows one to visualize the performance limits of a manufacturing system in terms of Work in Process, Throughput and Cycle Time. This technique has been introduced in the award-winning Factory Physics (FP) Book (Hopp and Spearman 2008), and is a key component of the science-based manufacturing management approach described in (Pound, Bell, and Spearman 2014). This post will use R to allow one to quickly run this analysis using the Basic Factory Dynamics equations found in the original FP books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of Simulation Models with Metamodels Part 1 - Low-Order Polynomials with Arena and R</title>
      <link>/post/making-sense-of-models-with-metamodels-low-order-polynomialss-with-arena-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-sense-of-models-with-metamodels-low-order-polynomialss-with-arena-and-r/</guid>
      <description>This is part 1 of a series of posts in which I will explore the utility of using metamodels to make sense of (and possibly optimizing) simulation models.
If you used simulation modeling on a real project, you might be familiar with this fictional story:
You spent long hours building and refining your simulation model (eg.: a Discrete Event Model). Hopefully, you are confident that it can yield reliable results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Decision Making in the 3D Printing Industry - 2018 DMDU Annual Meeting Materials</title>
      <link>/post/3d-printing-rdm-analysis-2018-dmdu-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/3d-printing-rdm-analysis-2018-dmdu-meeting/</guid>
      <description>This post contains materials related to the the presentation given at the 2018 DMDU Annual Meeting.
Full Master’s Thesis: Donwload Here.
Slides: Donwload Here.
Poster: Donwload Here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>